thames-water.com 2012-05-09

# Privacy policy - Thames Water

Last reviewed: 11.7.2011 - 8.17pm

Thames Water is committed to protecting your privacy and complying with the Data Protection Act 1998. This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  

In this privacy policy references to "we" and "us" are to Thames Water Ltd, Thames Water Utilities Ltd, and all subsidiary companies there of. 

## What information do we collect? 

We may collect store and process the following information that you provide to us via this website: 

  * Any personal details you submit to us such as name, address, email address etc. This includes information provided when you enter a competition or promotion; 
  * Any information you provide to us when we ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them; 
  * Payment details in respect of payments that you make via this website including payment card details and other transaction details. Please note - we do not retain credit verification numbers (CVCs); 
  * Opt in and opt out preferences that you provide to us via this website confirming whether you wish us (and selected third parties) to contact you with information and offers that may be of interest to you; 

## Using the information we collect 

We may use the information that we collect from you via this website in the following ways: 

  * In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws; 
  * For any particular use of the data specified at the time you provide it; 
  * To process any payments that you make via this website; and 
  * To contact you in any way (including mail, e-mail, phone, text) about products and services offered by us and selected partners. We will only contact you in this way if you have previously given your permission. 

We use a third party, [WorldPay UK Ltd](http://www.worldpay.com/ "WorldPay UK Ltd - link opens in a new window"), to collect your payment details process payments made over this website. 

If you provide us with sensitive personal information, you consent to the processing of this information for the purposes which you have provided it. 

## Your rights 

You can request a copy of the information that we hold about you at any time by contacting us at the address below. The provision of this information may be subject to the payment of a fee (currently £10). 

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually seek your consent if we intend to use your data for such purposes and you can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at the address below. 

Please let us know if the personal data that we hold about you needs to be updated by emailing us. 

Our site may contain links to and from this websites to websites of other organisations. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own Terms & Conditions and privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. 

## Security 

We will take appropriate technical and organisational measures to prevent the loss misuse or alteration of your personal information including the encryption of data using SSL technology. 

We will ensure that the personal information that you provide us via this website is held on secure servers. 

## Cookies 

The site may use 'cookies' which allow us to identify the computer used but not the individual user, record the areas of the site visited and recognise your computer when you return to the site. We do not track any information after you leave our site. 

## Updates to this privacy policy 

We may update this privacy policy from time to time and will state on the policy the date when the policy was last updated. 

## Contact 

Questions related to this privacy policy and access to any personal you have provided to us should be addressed to: 

Thames Water Data Protection Officer  
Clearwater Court  
Vastern Road  
Reading  
Berkshire  
RG1 8DB 

or complete our online enquiry form:

Online enquiry form

   Last updated: June 2011
